Guide to the William Boone Douglass papers, 1809-1948 RL.11831
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
William Boone Douglass papers
1809-1948
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Douglass, William Boone, 1864-1947
RL.11831
1884 items
William Boone Douglass was a lawyer, engineer, and surveyor, of Corydon (Harrison Co.), Ind. Collection includes correspondence, memorandum books, daybooks, notebooks on the Pueblo Indians, and other papers of Douglass and of various members of the Boone and Douglass families, especially of William's father, Benjamin P. Douglass, Indiana State Representative, and his son, William Boone Douglass, Jr., an official of the United States consular service. The letters pertain to the Kansas-Nebraska question, the passing of the first overland mail from California through Cassville, Mo., in 1858, elections to be held in Indiana in 1860, Douglass' surveying activities, establishment of a national park of the cliff cities of New Mexico, the securing of power from Boulder Dam, and other matters. Civil War letters from both Union and confederate soldiers are included; also an emancipation document for some enslaved people in Indiana Territory, designs submitted to the Patent Office, a biographical sketch of Douglass, and genealogical data on the Boone and related families.
Biographical / Historical
William Boone Douglass was a lawyer, engineer, and surveyor, of Corydon (Harrison Co.), Ind.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The William Boone Douglass papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library in 1951.
Collection Overview
Correspondence, memorandum books, daybooks, notebooks on the Pueblo Indians, and other papers of Douglass and of various members of the Boone and Douglass families, especially of William's father, Benjamin P. Douglass, Indiana State Representative, and his son, William Boone Douglass, Jr., an official of the United States consular service. The letters pertain to the Kansas-Nebraska question, the passing of the first overland mail from California through Cassville, Mo., in 1858, elections to be held in Indiana in 1860, Douglass' surveying activities, establishment of a national park of the cliff cities of New Mexico, the securing of power from Boulder Dam, and other matters. Civil War letters from both Union and confederate soldiers are included; also an emancipation document for some enslaved people in Indiana Territory, designs submitted to the Patent Office, a biographical sketch of Douglass, and genealogical data on the Boone and related families.
Kansas-Nebraska Act (United States); American Civil War (1861-1865); Aztec Ruins National Monument (N.M.); Hoover Dam (Ariz. and Nev.); Indiana -- Officials and employees.; Indiana -- Politics and government.; National parks and reserves -- New Mexico; Patents -- United States; Postal service -- United States -- History; Pueblo Indians; Tewa Indians; Slavery -- Indiana; Soldiers -- Confederate States of America -- Correspondence; Soldiers -- United States -- Correspondence; Surveyors -- Records; Diplomatic and consular service; Journals (accounts); Douglass, Benjamin P.; Boone family.; Douglas family.
- Letters, 1809-1889 (Box 1)
- Letters, 1890-1924 (Box 2)
- Letters, 1925-1932 (Box 3)
- Letters, 1933-1948 and undated (Box 4)
- Genealogy (Box 5)
- Miscellaneous papers, 1854-1937 (Box 6)
- Miscellaneous papers (Box 7)
- Miscellaneous papers (Box 8)
- Bound volumes (Box 9)
- Photographs (Box 10)
- Oversize materials (Oversize-folder 1)
- Notebook on Pueblo Indians, Vol. 1 (Volume M: 6372)
- Notebook on Pueblo Indians, Vol. 2 (Volume M: 5321)